Hello it's Scott Manley here.
你好 我是斯科特-曼利
Today I want to talk to you about weapons grade stuff.
今天我想和你谈谈武器级的东西
Now the term weapons grade has entered into popular power lines to the extent
现在 "武器级 "一词已经进入了流行的权力线 以至于我们目前正在谈论针对华尔街的武器级备忘录
that we are currently talking about weapons grade memes being deployed against Wall Street.
我们目前正在讨论针对华尔街部署的武器级备忘录
I'm gonna point out that you should not confuse this with military grade
我想指出的是 你不应该将其与军事级别相混淆
which is a completely meaningless term
这是一个完全没有意义的术语
generally added to Amazon listings to sell them to a certain type of person.
一般是加在亚马逊的清单上 以卖给某类人
Now weapons grade refers to weapons-grade material needed to make nuclear weapons.
现在 武器级是指制造核武器所需的武器级材料
And these basically set down constraints as to the isotope ratios for the material
这些材料基本上对材料的同位素比例作出了限制
so that they can be used to easily build bombs.
以便它们可以被用来轻易地制造炸弹
And the reason why of course we're interested in this is
当然 我们对此感兴趣的原因是
you want to keep that kind of material under control to stop it to stop nuclear proliferation.
你想把这种材料控制住 以阻止它来阻止核扩散
Now the origin of these terms I believe goes back to like the 1950s
现在 这些术语的起源我相信可以追溯到20世纪50年代
where the US is starting to collaborate on nuclear science with other nations
美国开始与其他国家在核科学方面进行合作
and they're looking at what level of uranium enrichment they can share
他们正在研究他们可以分享何种程度的铀浓缩
and there's this document that was published that figured out that
并有这样的文件 被公布 认为
for research reactors they shouldn't allow anything more than 20%
对于研究反应堆 他们不应该允许超过20％的东西
so 20% becomes the transition from low enriched uranium to highly enriched uranium.
因此 20%成为低浓缩铀到高浓缩铀的过渡
And weapons grade is like 80%.
而武器级是80%
Yeah depending upon the material, you've got different rules.
是的 根据材料的不同 你有不同的规则
For uranium it's all about the isotopic ratio of uranium-235
对于铀 它是所有关于铀235的同位素比率
which is the stuff that actually explodes and drives the chain reaction
这是实际爆炸和驱动链式反应的东西
and uranium-238 which sort of generally sits on the sidelines and doesn't do very much useful stuff.
和铀-238的同位素比例 后者通常坐在一边 不做非常有用的东西
Now in nature you've only got 0.7% uranium-235 in regular uranium and the rest is 99.3% uranium-238
现在 在自然界中 普通铀中只有0.7%的铀235 其余的是99.3%的铀238
so it is possible to make a nuclear reactor using just this regular material
因此 它是可能的 使一个核反应堆只用这种普通的材料
but you have to have a lot of moderators to slow down the neutrons
但你必须有大量的调节器 以减缓中子的速度
and get them to pay attention to the 235 and stop all those 238s from getting in the way.
并让它们注意到235 阻止所有这些238进入的方式
But if you go through a process of enrichment
但是 如果你通过一个浓缩的过程
where you exploit the very small differences in mass between these two atoms
你利用这两种原子之间非常小的质量差异
and you enhance the concentration of the uranium-235
而且你提高了铀235的浓度
then your reaction gets easier and easier to make.
那么你的反应就会变得越来越容易进行
Now for the first atom bomb drop from a plane that was a little boy
现在 第一颗原子弹从飞机上投下 是一个小男孩
and it was made with material that was on average 80% enriched.
它是用平均80%的浓缩材料制成的
I say on average because apparently large parts of it were 90% enriched
我说平均 因为很明显 它的很大一部分是90%的浓缩物
but there was some part which was only 50% enriched.
但也有一些部分只有50%的浓缩度
A lot of these details are uh still somewhat classified.
这些细节在某种程度上仍然是保密的
So it's relatively easy to make an atom bomb
因此 制造原子弹是比较容易的
if you have enough for uranium at 80 concentration enrichment, right.
如果你有足够的浓缩度为80的铀 对吧
As you get to lower and lower levels of enrichment you need larger and larger critical masses.
当你达到越来越低的浓缩水平时 你需要越来越大的临界质量
And like in theory I believe you can make 20% low enriched uranium go off.
就像在理论上 我相信你可以使20%的低浓缩铀爆炸
The point is that you you want to restrict these very high things from being available to the world
问题是 你想限制这些非常高的东西被提供给世界
and generally the only stuff that's really kept around these days is highly enriched.
而且一般来说 现在唯一真正保留的东西是高浓缩的
The highly enriched uranium is used in very limited number of cases.
高浓缩铀被用于非常有限的情况
Sometimes used in submarine reactors for example
有时用于潜艇反应堆 例如
where you want to get high power density and the least amount of stuff getting in the way.
在那里你想获得高功率密度和最少的东西得到的方式
Okay so plutonium.
好吧 那么钚
Now plutonium is actually what's used in most atom bombs these days.
现在 钚实际上是现在大多数原子弹中使用的东西
It's much better.
它好得多
It has much lower critical mass.
它的临界质量低得多
It's a lot harder to work with for various reasons.
由于各种原因 它更难处理
But it's generally become the thing of choice.
但它通常成为首选的东西
Now plutonium isn't a natural material.
现在 钚并不是一种天然材料
It's made in a reactor.
它是在反应堆中制造的
It's actually made where you have a regular chain reaction going with uranium-235
它实际上是在你有一个常规的连锁反应与铀235
and that uranium-238 that isn't doing anything useful.
和铀-238 没有做任何有用的东西
It will frequently absorb a neutron that will increase the mass to 239
它将经常吸收一个中子 将质量增加到239
and then it'll undergo a series of radioactive decays and you'll get plutonium-239.
然后 它将经历一系列的放射性衰变 你会得到钚239
So this is how they made the plutonium for the first atom bomb.
所以这就是他们为第一颗原子弹制造钚的方法
They built these reactors that didn't produce power.
他们建立了这些反应堆 不生产电力
They actually took power from the power grid.
他们实际上是从电网上获取电力
But they sustained this reaction
但他们维持这个反应
and they were able to take the materials out
他们能够采取的材料出来
reprocess them, extract the plutonium
重新处理它们 提取钚
and that was the material was used to make the trinity device
而这些材料被用来制造三位一体装置
which was the first atom bomb ever detonated.
这是有史以来引爆的第一颗原子弹
And of course later the fat man which was dropped over Nagasaki.
当然 后来在长崎上空投放的胖子也是如此
So with plutonium yeah the 239 is the stuff that explodes
因此 对于钚来说 239是爆炸的东西
but as it turns out the other isotopes pretty much all explode too.
但事实证明 其他同位素也几乎都会爆炸
However with a material in the reactor it's not just plutonium-239 you get.
然而 对于反应堆中的材料 你得到的不仅仅是钚239
You get other isotopes produced because you can't exactly control the series of reactions.
你会得到其他同位素的产生 因为你不能完全控制一系列的反应
Sometimes that 239 will absorb another neutron and it'll become plutonium-240.
有时 239会吸收另一个中子 变成钚-240
Sometimes there are other reactions that will produce plutonium-238
有时还有其他反应 会产生钚238
which is the stuff that is used in spacecraft for power generation.
这是在航天器中用于发电的东西
The problem is that both of these materials have drawbacks.
问题是 这两种材料都有缺点
The plutonium-240 is just as valid as a weapons material
钚-240作为一种武器材料同样有效
but it will undergo spontaneous fission more often
但它会更经常地发生自发裂变
and that means that it can trigger the reaction early.
而这意味着它可以提前触发反应
And I don't mean early as in when the bombs are sitting around doing nothing.
而我的意思不是指在炸弹无所事事时的早期
I mean that during the process of collapsing your material down into a critical mass
我的意思是 在把你的材料压缩成一个临界质量的过程中
you want to squish it as small as possible
你想把它压得越小越好
and it takes a finite amount of time to do that.
并且需要有限的时间来做到这一点
But if you've got too much plutonium-240 there
但是 如果你有太多的钚-240在那里
it can actually trigger the reaction while you are still squeezing things down
它实际上可以触发反应 而你仍然在挤压的东西
and that means you never reach your peak density and the bomb explodes with less energy
这意味着你永远不会达到你的峰值密度 炸弹爆炸的能量较小
because it has less new density.
因为它的新密度较小
So that's one problem.
所以这就是一个问题
The plutonium 240 by the way is the reason
顺便说一下 钚240的原因是
why they couldn't build a simple gun type device
为什么他们不能建立一个简单的枪型装置
where you shoot one slug into another and that makes your critical mass.
你把一个弹头射入另一个弹头 这就是你的临界质量
With that they figured out the barrel needed to be way too long
有了这个 他们发现枪管需要太长了
because plutonium's chance of predetonation was too high.
因为钚的预爆机会太高
So with weapons grades plutonium you make sure there's no more than 6.5% plutonium-240.
因此 对于武器级钚 你要确保其含量不超过6.5%的钚-240
The 238 as I said is used in spacecraft because it's radioactive.
正如我所说 238被用于航天器 因为它具有放射性
It generates a lot of heat.
它产生了大量的热量
So having too much heat in the device that you want to use is probably a problem.
因此 在你想使用的设备中 有太多的热量可能是一个问题
It means you have to somehow get rid of that heat
这意味着你必须以某种方式摆脱这种热量
or it will damage components damage your explosives.
否则就会损坏部件 损坏你的炸药
So the weapons grade material has less than one half of a% of plutonium-238 in there.
因此 武器级材料中的钚238含量不到一半
So that's your thing 93% plutonium-239 with 7% other stuff.
因此 这是你的东西93％的钚239和7％的其他东西
That's weapons grade.
这就是武器级
But again that's just what is easy to work with.
但这也只是容易处理的东西
As you get more and more other isotopes in there it is still possible to build weapons
当你得到越来越多的其他同位素在那里 它仍然有可能建立武器
and in 1962 Britain was working with the US
1962年 英国与美国合作
and they came along with some reactor grade material that had
他们带来了一些反应堆级的材料 其中有
but it's believed it was about 15% other isotopes
但据说有大约15%的其他同位素
and they used that to build a bomb to demonstrate that was possible.
他们用它来制造炸弹 以证明这是可能的
And it yeah.
它是的
It was a little weaker I believe it was only about 10 kilotons.
它有点弱 我相信它只有大约10千吨
But this is all classified.
但这都是机密
The exact numbers here are totally classified.
这里的确切数字是完全保密的
And I'm just guessing here.
而我只是在这里猜测
So it is possible.
所以它是可能的
I think there's another calculation I saw that said that
我想我看到的另一个计算方法是 说
going from like 5% other isotopes to 15% other isotopes cuts your weapon yield by a factor of 10
从5%的其他同位素到15%的其他同位素 使你的武器产量减少10倍
and then going from 15% to 25% cuts it by another factor of 10.
然后从15%增加到25% 再减少10个系数
But that's not to say that it's impossible
但这并不是说这是不可能的
it just gets harder and your yields get lower.
它只是变得更难 你的产量变得更低
So the thing about making the plutonium in the reactor is that
因此 关于在反应堆中制造钚的事情是
because you've got all these other side reactions
因为你有所有这些其他的副反应
reactors are designed to make fuel or fissile material for nuclear weapons
反应堆的设计是为了制造核武器的燃料或裂变材料
will generally only keep the rods in the reactor for a couple of weeks
通常只在反应堆中保留几个星期的棒子
and then take them out for reprocessing.
然后把它们拿出来进行再加工
But that in many reactor designs pressurized water designs means
但是 在许多反应堆设计中 压水设计意味着
shutting the entire reactor down letting it cool down and then taking the rods out.
关闭整个反应堆 让它冷却下来 然后把棒子拿出来
Whereas the reactors that were used to generate the plutonium for the first weapons
而用于产生第一种武器的钚的反应堆
they had this sort of continuous flow system where you pushed the rods in at one end
他们有这种连续流动的系统 你把棒子从一端推进去
it was horizontal and as you pushed it in it pushed the rods out the back
它是水平的 当你把它推入 它把棒子从后面推出来
so they could keep the fuel in the reactor for only a limited amount of time.
因此 他们可以保持燃料在反应堆中只有有限的时间
When you have the fuel sitting in the reactor for years
当你把燃料放在反应堆里好几年的时候
it generates much much more of these other reactants
它产生了更多的这些其他反应物
and so the material is not considered weapons grade
因此 该材料不被认为是武器级
unless you can somehow remove these.
除非你能以某种方式消除这些
So yeah that's again why you want to control reprocess nuclear material
所以 这也是为什么你要控制核材料的再加工
but equally it becomes very hard to build an atom bomb
但同样地 制造原子弹也变得非常困难
because of the problems of pre-detonation and heat.
因为有预爆炸和热量的问题
Now there is one other nuclear material that's worth mentioning
现在还有一种值得一提的核材料
and that is uranium-233.
那就是铀233
That's another isotope o'f uranium that in many ways is actually better than uranium-235.
这是另一种铀的同位素 在许多方面实际上比铀235更好
You actually need a lower critical mass of uranium-233.
你实际上需要一个较低临界质量的铀233
So uranium-233 comes from thorium reactors.
因此 铀233来自于钍反应堆
When thorium-232 which is the most common isotope absorbs a neutron
当钍-232（最常见的同位素）吸收了一个中子后
it transmutes into uranium-233
它转化为铀-233
and then that's the stuff that actually undergoes fission in these reactors.
然后这就是在这些反应堆中实际发生裂变的东西
And again yeah you can use this in bombs.
再说一遍 你可以在炸弹中使用这个
It was been tested. The US has tested a weapon.
它已经被测试过了 美国已经测试了一种武器
I believe India might have tested a weapon with this.
我相信印度可能已经用它试验了一种武器
The problem is that again it's a material produced in a reactor
问题是 这也是一种在反应堆中产生的材料
and you have other materials other isotopes produced.
而且你还有其他材料和其他同位素的生产
And the biggest problem is uranium-232 that can result
最大的问题是可能产生铀-232
and on its own it's fine right.
而它本身是好的 对吗？
It'll actually undergo fission too.
它实际上也会发生裂变
But it decays into a whole bunch of other decay products
但它会衰变成一大堆其他衰变产物
which produce a lot of gamma rays.
这产生了大量的伽马射线
And so I believe anything more than about 50 parts per million of uranium-232 in your sample
所以我相信 如果你的样品中铀-232的含量超过百万分之五十 就很难进行处理
makes it very hard to work with because of the amount of gamma radiation.
就很难处理 因为有大量的伽马辐射
You have to move to like shielded glove box or remote manipulation rather than simply glove boxes.
你必须转移到像屏蔽的手套箱或远程操作 而不是简单的手套箱
So this 50 parts per million requirement is really hard to achieve.
所以这个百万分之五十的要求真的很难实现
And it's one of the reasons why thorium reactors are usually cited by their proponents
这也是钍反应堆的支持者通常将其列为扩散风险很低的原因之一
as being a very low proliferation risk.
作为一个非常低的扩散风险
So yeah that's that's what weapons grade means.
所以 是的 这就是武器级的含义
It's all about the isotope ratios of all these different materials.
这都是关于所有这些不同材料的同位素比率
There's probably other fissile materials where the concept of weapons grade has been considered.
可能还有其他裂变材料也被认为是武器级的概念
You can make a bomb with neptunium, californium, americium. I had never had to know how to pronounce that.
你可以用镎、锎、镅制作炸弹 我从来没有必要知道如何发音
But it's a thing that makes stuff explode.
但它是一种能让东西爆炸的东西
So yes now you all know.
所以是的 现在你们都知道了
Weapons grade material. Make sure you've got your percentages laid out.
武器级材料 请确保你已经得到了你的百分比
Otherwise you won't get the boom boom that you want.
否则 你不会得到你想要的轰鸣声
I'm Scott Manley. Fly safe.
我是斯科特-曼利 飞行安全
[Music]
[音乐]